MARTIN RANNEKLEV
143-43 232nd Street
Laurelton Manor, N.Y. 11413
Home (718) 712-2835
Cell (718) 772-6169
Martinisok@aol.com

SUMMARY/GOALS: Over thirty years of Computer Aided Design (CAD) experience, latest Software worked with 2020 MEP, Navis Works Manager & Revit. Experienced in PC evaluation & procurement, installation, & management related to all CAD software & hardware. I have been involved creating 3D MEP Models for coordination and using Navis Manager to resolve clash reports for signed off drawings from which to create shop drawings for the field. I've done field measurements from Cooling Towers to Machine Rooms and VRF systems. My goals include using state of the art technology to create accurate 3D models in a timely manner & the opportunity to create exciting new designs & programs through my expertise, for a progressive, challenging, team oriented company with an eye towards the future in which I can contribute. I am immediately available for freelancing & or full-time employment.

EMPLOYMENT

03/2018 – 10/2021: **Tristate Air Conditioning, inc.: 113 Bloomingdale rd. Hicksville NY 11801:** MEP2020, Revit, Navis Manager, Word, Excel & Adobe Pro. Currently hoping to go back to work for them, pending work slow down due to Covid-19.

10/2017 – 1/2018: **McClure Company, Harrisburg, PA**: MEP modeling contract work assignment, I completed a HVAC piping & Plumbing model for them using Autodesk MEP, Revit & Navis Manager. I am now looking another contract assignment or full time job.

3/2014- 5/2017: **United Air Conditioning., Long Island City, NY**: Lead CAD Draftsman: BIM modeling for Coordination meetings using 3-D with Autodesk MEP, Revit & Navis Manager & revised drawings accordingly & made shop & As-Built drawings. Job site visits for field measurements & photos of pipe, which were added to CAD files for clarity of details & field conditions.

2/2013- 5/2013: **Alfa Piping, Inc., Long Island City, NY**: Lead CAD Draftsman: made shop & As-Built drawings using Autodesk MEP. Participated in coordination meetings & revised drawings accordingly. Job site visits for field measurements & photos of pipe, which were added to CAD files for clarity of details & field conditions.

9/2006 - 2/2013: **KSW Mechanical Services, Inc., Long Island City, NY:** CAD Draftsman: Created shop & As-Built drawings, revised coordination drawings. Also created details for mechanical requirements according to specifications. Plotted & scanned full E-size drawings & larger, both color & black & white.

12/2005 - 3/2006: **ABCO Peerless Fire Sprinklers, Hicksville, NY:** CAD Draftsman: Designed shop & As-Built drawings. Enjoyed working with this company & expected to be there for years, but slow sales caused cut backs & being the most recent hire, I was the first economic casualty of the Sales Department.

6/2005 - 12/2005: **NY Elevator: NYC:** CAD Draftsman: Managing & drawing CAD files for Engineering Department, surveying jobs; creating As-Built drawings; filing DOB form NYC work permits. I left for new job offering me a higher salary & shorter commute.

11/1999 - 7/2004: **Port Authority of NY& NJ: JFK International Airport:** CAD Consultant: Worked on Utility Management System; responsible for sending Markout & Survey crews out for verifications of site utilities; scrubbing As-Built drawings & reformatting to the Port Authority's CAD Standards; providing maps of the latest & most up to date information to the Engineering Dept., as well as designers for the on-going construction & redevelopment of JFK International Airport. Data input for structures & line work for CAD records, including survey point files; updating MDB files, dwg blocks, working with LandDevelopment4 for AutoCAD2004 & updating to Mapguide6 & various associated programs, & backups.

1/1997 - 7/1999: **Sirina Fire Protection, Inc. Garden City, NY**: Engineer/CAD Operator: In charge of all CAD related equipment for Engineering Dept. at Sirina Fire Protection, Inc. Duties include plotting submittal, shop & coordination drawings, & handling X-refs for JFK Airport Terminal 4 @ JFK Airport. Coordination & submittals mainly handled over the Internet & via email. Also file back up & PC maintenance for CAD stations. Scope of work included pipe racks, risers, sprinkler layouts primarily for Terminal 4 JFK Airport & updating As-Built drawings for Terminal 7; Korean Air, & a variety of other commercial projects, including 4 & 5 Times Square projects & Planet Hollywood in NYC. Initial training in Bidcom Software for facility at 745 Park Ave. South NY, NY. Sprinkler design & calculation using Haas software for sprinkler calculations & acquainted with SprinkCad from Central Sprinklers.

7/1996 – 1/1997: **Zwicker Electric, Inc. NYC:** Engineer/CAD Operator: AutoCAD Draftsman for Electrical Contract Submittal & Shop & Coordination drawings. Scope of work included pipe racks & risers, as well light layouts primarily for the 4 Times Square Building in NY, NY & other NYC projects.

4/1994 - 7/1996: **Vicale Corp: Danbury CT:** Engineer/CAD Operator: AutoCAD Draftsman creating 3D models & Renders of Design Concepts, drafting Mechanical, Shop & Patent Drawings. Originally started 6 months previously on freelance basis before coming on board full time in 4/1995.

1994 - 1996: N.C. Design: Katonah, NY: CAD Operator: Drafting Design Concepts, Proto-types, Mechanical, Shop & Patent Drawings, as well as 3D models & renders for presentation in AutoCAD R13 on a freelance basis.

1/94 - 2/94: **C.M. Engineering: Armonk, NY**: CAD Operator: prepared Architectural drawings (wall structures, stairwells, elevations & assorted details) on AutoCAD R12.

1976 - 1994: Ranneklev Brothers, Inc., Katonah NY: Carpenter: Built high-end custom homes. Expert in trimming, framing, siding, roofing & estimating.

EDUCATION

John Jay High School - 1976 Westchester Community College 1979: General Studies New York Institute of Technology 1980: Architecture Control Data Institute - 1983-1984: Mainframe trouble shooting Westchester Community College 1991-1993: AutoCAD

Accumulated approximately 3000 hours of AutoCAD, training related to AutoCAD Releases 11 & 12, R12 & R13 for Windows, 2D, AME & 3D modeling, AutoArchitect, AutoLISP. Most recently I've been working with Autodesk MEP 2017 & Navis works Manager 2017 & Revit for exporting Revit files into AutoCAD dwg files. I have been using Autodesk software for the last 24 years professionally.

I also have my own licensed copy Architectural Desktop2006 & CorelDraw12 & am willing to freelance my skills on site or over the web. Proficient in AutoCAD

R17; experienced with AutoCAD LandDevelopment Desktop & MapGuide; proficient in Word, Excel, Access, Corel Draw, Adobe Illustrator, WordPerfect & 3D Studio Max.